压力压在我身上
♪ Pressure pushing down on me ♪
按下你没有人要求♬
♪ Pressing down on you No man ask for ♪
在压力下烧毁了一座建筑
♪ Under pressure That burns a building down ♪
将一个家庭一分为二♬
♪ Splits a family in two ♪
让人们走上街头♬
♪ Puts people on streets ♪
这是知道的恐惧
♪ It's the terror of knowing ♪
这个世界到底是怎么回事
♪ What this world is about ♪
♬看一些好朋友♬
♪ Watching some good friends ♪
尖叫着“放我出去”♬
♪ Screaming, "Let me out"♪
祈祷明天能让我走得更高
♪ Pray tomorrow Gets me higher ♪
人的压力街上的人♬
♪ Pressure on people People on streets ♪
-剧毒
-  It's highly toxic.
加油，伙计们，继续前进
Come on, lads, keep it moving.
保持运动
Keep it moving.
快，快，快!
Go, go, go!
这是双倍工资吗?
Is this double pay or what?
有有毒的废物
There is toxic waste.
你坐在那儿干什么，伙计?
What are you doing sitting there, mate?
-你就快到了
- You're almost there.
我要这些垃圾尽快离开我的飞船
I want this filth off my ship as fast as possible.
那你在干什么?
What you doing, then?
淘气
Naughty.
的帮助!的帮助!
Help! Help!
淘气
Naughty.
嘘
Shh.
-闭上你的小嘴
- Keep your little beak shut.
不是很好
Not very nice.
否则，你就去游泳
Otherwise, you'll go for a swim.
——帮助!的帮助!
- Help! Help!
帮帮我!帮帮我!
Help me! Help me!
-嗨 ——啊 做得很好
- Hey. - Ah. Well done.
我是从总部来的
I'm here from the home office.
废话
Bullshit.
在这里检查安全协议…
Here checking on, uh, security protocols...
…然后拍几张照片，所以笑一笑
...and, um, taking a few pictures, so smile.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing in here?
-不太好 -怎么回事?
-  Not very nice. - What's going on?
这是他!
That's him!
-我会抓到你的!
- I'll get you!
嘿,嘿!抓住这个!
Hey, hey! Get at this!
-起来 -把他放下来!
-  Get up. -  Get Him down!
你们两个，往左边走!打断他!
You two, go left! Cut him off!
我要抓住他，不管他是死是死
I want him caught, dead or dead.
不存在!绕!绕!
Not there! Go around! Go around!
给你，伙计 结束了
There you go, mate. End of the line.
好吧
Okay.
你们都被捕了
You're all under arrest.
——嗯?-因为非法倾倒
-  Huh? - For the illegal dumping
-指放射性物质
- of radioactive materials.
是啊，你，你，你，还有你
Yeah, you, you, you, you and you.
什么，我和…还有他，还有他?和他?
What, me and... and him, and him? And him?
-杀了他 -等等，等等，等等，等等
- Kill him. -  Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
我知道 你想看搜查令
I know. You want to see the warrant.
就在我的口袋里
It's right in my pocket.
法庭上见，好吗?
I'll see you in court, yeah?
我们不在航线上，
We're out of shipping lanes,
你离海岸有200英里
and you're 200 miles from shore.
祝你游泳愉快
So enjoy your swim.
我抓住他了 就在左舷那边
I've got him. Just off the port side.
他就像一个绿色的詹姆斯·邦德 我喜欢它 </ I >
He's like a green James Bond. I like it.
哦，不，我的帽子!
Oh, no, my hat!
你好,傻瓜
Hello, suckers.
看来他交了不少朋友
Looks like he's been making friends.
无论他走到哪里，人们都喜欢他
Wherever he goes, people just love him.
天知道为什么
God knows why.
你明白了吗?
Do you got this?
我们将会看到
We'll see.
也许这不是个好主意
Maybe this wasn't the best idea.
Maybe this isn't the best idea.
这一定会很棒的
This is gonna be awesome.
定义“酷毙了”
Define "awesome."
我正要去
I'm about to.
-打开舱门
- Opening hatch.
下次，多给这东西充气
Next time, put a little more air in this thing.
就像用吸管呼吸一样
It's like breathing through a straw.
起作用了，不是吗?
Worked, didn't it?
你没事吧?
You okay?
如果你热爱你的工作，
If you love your job,
你一辈子都不用工作
you'll never work a day in your life.
好的，引入Test 15
Okay, bring in Test 15.
启动套装升级
Initiating suit power-up.
明确的
Clear.
有前途
Promising.
exo服的表现远远超出了我们的预期，九明
The exo suit is performing way beyond what we expected, Jiuming.
功率增加21%
21% increase in power.
不错吧?
Not bad, huh?
太酷了
So cool.
我等不及要在战壕里用这个了
I can't wait to use these in the trench.
嗨
Hi.
怎么了，亲爱的侄女?
What's up favourite niece?
我应该告诉你今晚的聚会不要迟到
I'm supposed to tell you not to be late for the party tonight.
当然可以
Of course.
-大概25吧 嗯?——好的
-  Maybe 25. Hmm? - Okay.
我是认真的，不要迟到!
I mean it, don't be late!
真不敢相信你能走到这一步
I cannot believe you got this far in life
不知道怎么打领带
without knowing how to tie a tie.
首先，不要夸大我在生活中取得的成就
First, let's not overstate how far I've gotten in life.
第二，不要穿猴子装
Second, never involved wearing a monkey suit.
——完美 你看起来很好 ——谢谢
- Perfect. You look great. - Thanks.
啊 也许这是一个开始
Ah. Maybe this is the start of something.
别指望它
Don't count on it.
嗨
Hi.
你觉得那个人眼熟吗?
That guy look familiar to you?
不
No.
-我不喜欢他 -你谁都不喜欢
-  I don't like him. - You don't like anyone.
我喜欢你
I like you.
那是因为我一直在救你的命
That's 'cause I save your life all the time...
我给你买啤酒，支持你
I buy you beers and I back you up
在酒吧打架
in bar fights.
因为你是个特别的人
It's 'cause you're a special guy.
你们俩都很特别
You're both special.
-祝我好运 -祝你好运
- Wish me luck. -  Good luck.
谢谢你的钱
Thanks for the money.
女士们，先生们，
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎参加十周年庆典
welcome to the 10th anniversary
of the Oceanic Institute.
我是Hilary Driscoll
I'm Hilary Driscoll.
感谢你今晚的到来，和我在一起
Thank you for coming tonight, and for joining me
为这项不可思议的工作提供资金
in funding this incredible work.
停止 不要坐立不安
Stop. Don't fidget.
我到底为什么要做
Why exactly do I have to be
反正在这里?
up here anyway?
因为你很有团队精神
'Cause you're a team player.
太好了
Great.
请给予热烈的欢迎
Please give a warm welcome
致研究所所长…
to the director of the Institute...
<我>…张Jiuming < / i >
...Zhang Jiuming.
谢谢你，希拉里
Thank you, Hilary.
正如伟大的诗人宋濂所说……
As the great poet Song Lian said...
“人只受想象力的限制 ”
"Man is limited only by his imagination."
我父亲给我起名叫九明，
My father named me Jiuming,
意思是海洋
which means ocean
或深渊
or abyss.
我爸爸和我妹妹
My father and my sister
他们一生都在研究海洋
spent their lives studying the ocean.
直到
It wasn't until
他们都走了，我开始怀疑
they were both gone that I began to wonder
我的目的是什么
what my purpose was.
但通过苏音的女儿美英
But through Suyin's daughter Meiying,
我看到了未来
I saw that there was a future.
我合并了我父亲的研究所
I merged my father's research institute
和我的公司
with my company
发扬光大
to carry forward
以他们的名义探索未知的精神
the spirit of exploring the unknown in their honor.
为了纪念十周年，
To mark this tenth anniversary,
我想给大家介绍一位非常特别的人
I want to introduce you all to someone very special.
她的名字叫海琪
Her name is Haiqi.
她是世界上唯一一只被囚禁的巨齿鲨
She is the world's only megalodon in captivity.
我们发现她小时候受了伤
We found her injured as a pup.
感谢海琪，我们学到了很多东西
Thanks to Haiqi, we've learned a tremendous amount
关于巨齿鲨
about the megalodons
还有他们生活的战壕
as well as the trench where they live.
感谢慷慨的捐赠
Thanks to the generous donations
来自我们的支持者，
from our supporters,
我们已经能够创造技术
we have been able to create the technology
穿过温跃层，
to pass through the thermocline,
结冰的冷水热层
a thermal layer of freezing cold water
分隔海琪的世界和我们的世界
that separates Haiqi's world from ours
并进入海拔6000米以下的海沟
and into a trench 6,000 meters below sea level.
多亏了你，我们才有能力
Thanks to you, we have the ability
比以前走得更远
to go further than ever before.
爱护海洋，保护海洋
Love the ocean and protect the ocean.
谢谢你！
Thank you
谢谢你 张Jiuming < / i >
And thank you. Zhang Jiuming.
谢谢大家
So, thank you all
作为保护这个不可思议的生态系统的一部分
for being part of protecting this incredible ecosystem.
谢谢你的光临
Thank you for coming.
你觉得还有其他生物吗
Do you think there are more creatures
在那里被发现?
to be discovered down there?
肯定有
There has to be.
谁想自拍
Who wants to get a selfie
with the man
谁与巨齿鲨搏斗并活下来讲述这个故事?< / i >
who fought a megalodon and lived to tell the tale?
女士们，先生们，我们给你们，
We give you, ladies and gentlemen,
< / i > <我>乔纳斯泰勒
Jonas Taylor.
- -他在那儿!他来了
- - There he is! There he is.
我知道这是你的主意
I know this was your idea.
-我要杀了你
- I'm gonna kill you.
微笑，假装你喜欢它
Smile and pretend you love it.
来，给他一个拥抱 给他搔搔痒
Go on, give him a hug. Give him a tickle.
哦，他喜欢人
Oh, he loves people.
我想和你一起去玛娜一号
I wanna go to Mana One with you.
我想潜入战壕
I want to dive the trench.
不
No.
对不起,Meiying
Sorry, Meiying.
为什么不呢?
Why not?
妈妈在我这个年纪的时候一直在潜水
Mom was diving all the time at my age.
不到25000英尺
Not to 25,000 feet.
说太危险了?
Saying it's too dangerous?
对你来说太危险了
Too dangerous for you.
但并不危险
But not dangerous.
在心理学上，他们称之为“认知失调”
In psychology, they call that "cognitive dissonance."
在现实世界中，他们称之为“养育子女”
In the real world, they call it "parenting."
你得开始认真对待我了
You need to start taking me seriously
作为一个科学家
as a scientist.
-你才14岁 ——没错
- You're 14. - Exactly.
我知道玛娜一号上的所有系统，
I know every system on Mana One,
每个潜水协议
every dive protocol
以及我们在那里见过的所有动物
and every animal we've seen down there.
嘿,你看
Hey, look.
你可以来玛娜一号
You can come to Mana One.
观察潜水
To observe the dive.
就是这样
And that's it.
九明正在和巨齿鲨一起游泳
Jiuming is swimming with the meg.
叔叔
Uncle.
海琪的生命体征升高了
Haiqi's vitals are elevated.
小心点，她肯定注意到你了
Be careful, she's definitely aware of you.
你为什么游泳
Why are you swimming
和meg在一起，九明?< / i >
with the meg, Jiuming?
我正在做一个实验
I'm conducting an experiment.
这个实验是"我好吃吗"
Is the experiment "Do I taste good?"
叔叔，你疯了吗?
Uncle, are you crazy?
<我>没关系 < / i >
It's okay.
我从海琪还是只小狗的时候就开始训练她了
I've been training Haiqi since she was a pup.
meg是不可训练的，九明
A meg is not trainable, Jiuming.
但如果你想被吃掉
But if you wanna be eaten
在你侄女面前，说吧
in front of your niece, go ahead.
我赌五十块，肯定不会有好结果
Fifty bucks says this is gonna end badly.
我会采取行动的
I'll take that action.
我全力支持鲨鱼队
I am all in for team shark.
怎么啦？你不能在鲨鱼身上下注，伙计
What? You can't bet on a shark, man.
这是恶业
That's bad karma.
来吧，伙计们，集中精神 这一点都不酷
Come on, guys, focus. That's not cool.
Jiuming……
Jiuming...
我谨建议
I'd like to respectfully suggest
这真是个糟糕的主意
that this is truly a terrible idea.
梅格斯和人类从来就不该混在一起
Megs and humanity were never meant to mix.
我和海琪有一种特殊的感情
Haiqi and I have a special bond.
<我>看 < / i >
Watch this.
一键来 点击两下就可以了
One click to come. Two clicks to go.
哇 我觉得她在看我们
Whoa. I think she's looking at us.
<我>你看到了吗?< / i >
You see?
她正在回心转意 心率加快了
She's coming around. Heart rate is up.
-行动迅速
- Moving in fast.
四百米
Four hundred meters.
慢慢地,慢慢地
Slowly, slowly.
九明，她没反应
Jiuming, she's not responding.
加油，海琪
Come on, Haiqi.
两百米
Two hundred meters.
- 100米 ——< / i >
- One hundred meters. -
Jiuming,那就动起来吧
Jiuming, move.
太迟了 她来得太快了
It's too late. She's coming in too fast.
< / i > <我> 50米
Fifty meters.
拉绳子
Pull the cord.
< / i > <我> 20米
Twenty meters.
九明，快出来!< / i >
Jiuming, get out of there!
-叔叔，不要!——< / i >
-  Uncle, no! -
它打中他了吗?
Did it get him?
我不知道 我无法观看
I don't know. I couldn't watch.
我没看见他
I don't see him.
我就知道这不是个好主意
I knew this was a bad idea.
完全的成功
Total success.
叔叔!你疯了吗?
Uncle! Are you crazy?
没关系，我很好
It's all right, I'm good.
嗯?
Huh?
很刺激，对吧?
That was exciting, huh?
我不知道她怎么了
I can't figure out what's wrong with her.
她整个星期都表现得很奇怪
She's been acting strangely all week.
你可以随心所欲地点击
You can clickety-click all you want.
问题是它是巨齿鲨
The problem is that it's a meg.
而你是点心
And you're a snack.
-是的
-  Yeah.
郑重声明，你吓死美英了
For the record, you scared the hell out of Meiying.
你有资格说话
You're one to talk.
你在那艘船上干什么?
What were you doing on that ship?
其实，别告诉我 我不想知道
Actually, don't tell me. I don't wanna know.
这是研究所的任务
Well, the Institute's mandate
是为了保护海洋，对吗?
is to protect the oceans, right?
我们不能参与任何非法活动
We can't be a part of any illegal activity.
哦，我憎恶无法无天
Oh, I abhor lawlessness.
哦,很好
Oh, good.
特别是非法倾倒放射性废物
Especially the illegal dumping of radioactive waste.
你在冒越来越大的风险
You're taking bigger and bigger risks
每次你出去
each time you go out.
我想我们都心知肚明
Well, I guess we both know about that.
这是不一样的
It's not the same.
和我在一起,
With me,
这是对风险的计算
there's a calculation of risks.
我看没有
Not that I see.
你想妈妈吗，大鱼?
Do you miss your mom, big fish?
-霍华德医生
-  Doctor Howard.
你准备好了吗?
Are you ready for Mana One?
好的，什么时候准备好?
Yes, whenever you're ready?
这些新宇航服可以让我们在水下任何深度、任何地方旅行
These new suits will let us travel anywhere and at any depth underwater.
说
Say.
——什么?
- What?
别担心，别担心
No worries, no worries.
妈妈和爷爷一直在谈论你
Mom and Grandpa talked about you all the time.
我想没什么好东西
Nothing good I suppose.
想猜吗?
Wanna guess?
看到这个伤疤了吗?
See this scar?
当我11岁的时候，我父亲在实验室里很忙
When I was 11 my father was busy in the lab.
所以我偷偷溜出去和朋友们在岩石海岸游泳……
So I snuck out to swim with my friends on the rocky shores...
结果缝了九针
and had to get nine stitches as a result of it.
当我回到家时，我父亲给了我一个真正的教训
When I returned home my father taught me a real lesson.
——爷爷?-当然
- Grandpa? - Of course.
他对你很好，因为你是他孙女，
He was kind to you because you're his granddaughter,
但他对我很严厉
but he was tough on me.
大学毕业后，我开了一家公司
So after college, I started a company.
我想离开他
I wanted to get away from him.
我已经很多年没和你祖父联系了
I hadn't had any contact with your grandfather for many years.
然后他让你妈妈把这个书法给我
Then he asked your mum to bring me this calligraphy.
"龙穿越四海"
"Dragon travelling across the Four Seas."
我认为这是一种嘲笑……
I thought it was a form of ridicule...
但我开始意识到他希望我找到自己的路
but I came to realize that he wanted me to find my own way.
像龙一样……
Like the dragon...
我希望你能找到自己的命运
I hope you can find your own fate.
地勤人员，我们正在接近玛娜一号
Ground crew, we're approaching Mana One.
<我>嘿,里加斯 很高兴你能回来
Hey, Rigas. Good to have you back.
我想念你们
I missed you guys.
你准备好潜水了吗?< / i >
Are you ready to do some diving?
你知道的
You know it.
大家早上<我> . < / i >
Morning, everyone.
让我们在水下表演
Let's get this show underwater.
潜水1和潜水2，下降到25000英尺
Dive 1 and Dive 2, descend to 25,000 feet.
我们正在探索19区
We're exploring Area 19.
收集岩石样本并记录任何新物种
Collecting rock samples and logging any new species.
在t - 20分钟内潜水
Diving in T-minus 20 minutes.
All eyes open
表示直接的扫描 往常一样 < / i >
for a straightforward sweep and scan. The usual.
是的 那里没有惯例
Yeah. There's no usual down there.
-系统启动了
- System's up.
你这些玩具是怎么回事
What's with all these toys you have
在你的控制台附近晃荡，兰斯?
hanging around your console, Lance?
它们不是玩具，是小雕像
They're not toys, they're figurines.
它们绝对是玩具，兰斯
They are definitely toys, Lance.
-谢谢
- Thank you.
准备好了吗，伙计们?< / i >
Ready for the drop, guys?
你和萨尔是参加动漫展的人吗?
So, are you and Sal, like, Comic-Con guys or what?
完全正确 是的
Uh, absolutely right. Yeah.
你会打扮一下吗?
Do you, um, dress up?
嗯,是的
Uh, yeah.
别让他开始，除非你想看
Don't get him started, unless you want to see
一百万张照片
a million photographs.
哦，好的
Oh, yes, please.
保持专注，伙计们
Stay focused, guys.
<我> 17000 < / i >
Passing 17,000.
<我>遥测很好 < / i >
Telemetry's good.
今天附近天气很好
It's a beautiful day in the neighborhood.
超过18000英尺
Passing 18,000 feet.
所有系统都是标准的
All systems nominal.
看起来不错，伙计们
Looking good, team.
我们把今天要绘制的网格调出来
Let's pull up the grids we're gonna map today.
<我>面积19 < / i >
Area 19.
我们什么时候才能看到不同的东西?< / i >
When are we going to look at something different?
你知道，还有100多个领域等着你去探索
You know, there's like 100 more sectors to explore.
乔纳斯，你能确认一下血氧水平吗?
Jonas, can you confirm O2 levels?
消耗超过任务规格11%
Consumption is 11% over mission spec.
我猜里加斯很紧张
Guess Rigas is nervous.
更像是用嘴呼吸
More like you're a mouth breather.
-他确实是
- He totally is.
从这里可以感受到微风
Can feel the breeze from over here.
是的
Yeah.
首先，它被称为鼻中隔偏曲
Firstly, it's called a deviated septum.
第二，我清楚地记得我偏离了它
Second, I distinctly remember deviating it
一边救你这个忘恩负义的混蛋
while saving your ungrateful ass
来自一条70英尺长的巨齿鲨
from a 70-foot megalodon.
超过20000英尺 接近温跃层
Passing 20,000 feet. Approaching the thermocline.
检查氧气管路和储罐压力
Checking O2 lines and tank pressure.
如果有泄漏，
Well, if there was a leak,
读数会有波动
there would be a fluctuation on the readings.
我没有看到任何东西
I'm not seeing anything here.
检查副氧气罐压力
Check the pressure on the auxiliary O2 tanks.
好的，我再检查一下
Okay, I'll check again.
这不是问题所在
That's not the problem.
呃,乔纳斯?
Uh, Jonas?
Meiying吗?
Meiying?
你到底在干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
你在开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
我知道你很生气
I see that you're angry.
但我相信这是合理的
But I believe that this is a reasonable
负责任的决定
and responsible decision.
停止俯冲
Stop the dive.
句号
Full stop.
但在你开始大喊大叫之前，我能说…
But before you start yelling, can I just say...
我做了很多蠢事
I did all kinds of stupid things
我14岁的时候
when I was 14.
看看我现在的样子
And look how I turned out.
我们正在浮出水面
We're surfacing.
但我看不出有什么问题
But I don't see what the problem is.
这是你第26次顺利潜入战壕
This is your 26th trench dive without incident.
潜艇有电捕食者对抗装置，
Subs have electric predator countermeasures,
还有紧急潜水服
and emergency dive suits.
而你没有
Which you don't have.
实际上……
Actually...
你准备潜水前会议的时候我打包了一个
I packed one while you were doing the pre-dive meeting.
你知道的,
You know,
现在也许是时候，
now's maybe a good time to, uh,
坐下来，安静一会儿
sit down and be quiet for a minute.
我可以自己系安全带
I can do a seatbelt by myself, you know.
我知道你可以
I know you can.
<我>乔纳斯 < / i >
Jonas.
这不是你说了算的，九明
It's not your call, Jiuming.
有人来了
We've got company.
伙计们，这是巨齿鲨
Guys, it's a meg.
- -< i>正在快速接近
- -  Approaching fast.
那不可能
That's not possible.
它们不能穿过温跃层
they can't go through the thermocline.
它不是来自温跃层
It's not come from the thermocline.
我在岸上追踪它
I'm tracking it from the shore.
潜水!侧面速度!
Dive! Flank speed!
迷人 重新路由电池阵列
Engaging. Rerouting battery array.
<我> < / i >
Hold on.
攻击捕食者的对抗措施
Charging the predator countermeasures.
他们还没上网，我们就死了
We'll be dead before they're online.
温跃层是我们唯一的希望
Thermocline's our only hope.
我在读海琪的追踪器
I'm reading Haiqi's tracker.
不可能的
Impossible.
不可能变成了可能
Well, impossible just got possible.
500米到温跃层
Five hundred meters to the thermocline.
海琪正在快速靠近
Haiqi's closing fast.
100米
One hundred meters.
她就在我们上面
She's right above us.
加油，加油!
Come on, come on!
进入温跃层
Entering the thermocline.
俯冲1，俯冲2
Dive 1, Dive 2.
切换到低频灯
Switch to low-frequency light.
你不想吸引更多的妹子
you don't want to attract any more megs.
我失去她了
I've lost her.
她跟不上我们
She can't follow us through.
<我>可以吗?< / i >
Can she?
<我> < / i >
Going dark.
我从来没有以60节的速度越过温跃层
I've never crossed the thermocline at 60 knots.
<我>小心 你可不想把引擎烧坏
Careful. You don't want to burn out the engines.
别担心，我不会弄坏这些漂亮玩具的
Don't worry, I'm not gonna break the pretty toys.
是的
Yes.
她还在追我们
She's still on us.
<我> < / i >三十秒
Thirty seconds
-为对策 ——逃避
- for the countermeasures. - Evasive.
她一定是跟踪了我们的热信号
She must have followed our heat signature.
你的宠物鲨鱼怎么样
How did your pet shark
你给我下来，九明?< / i >
get down here, Jiuming?
她一定是逃走了
She must have escaped.
这是怎么发生的?
How did that happen?
捕食者对抗激活
Predator countermeasures active.
接近警戒
Proximity alert.
兆
Megs.
不可能
No way.
这是我见过的最大的巨齿鲨
That's the biggest meg I've ever seen.
前所未见的巨鲨
Biggest meg anyone's ever seen.
那一定是顶级掠食者
That's gotta be the apex predator.
<我>难以置信 meg是孤立的
Incredible. Megs are solitary.
就像他们在被召唤
It's like they're being called.
我要改变潜水计划
I'm changing the dive plan.
我们得看看他们想干什么
We have to see what they're up to.
那美英呢?
And what about Meiying?
好吧，我建议我们去
Well, I vote we go.
我没问你
I wasn't asking you.
氧储量达到最大值
Oxygen reserves are at maximum.
已经部署捕食者对抗措施
Predator countermeasures are deployed.
现在我们非常安全
Right now we are perfectly safe.
现在，是的
Right now, yeah.
如果我发现任何危险，我就会撤资
If I see anything dangerous, I'm pulling the plug.
Mac，我们在修改
Mac, we're changing
任务概要
the mission profile.
继续标题227
Proceeding on heading 227.
现在，他们已经离开任务了
Now, they're already off mission.
他们需要保持航向
They need to stay on course.
乔纳斯，你太过分了
Jonas, you're going way outside
我们已经绘制的区域
the sector we have already mapped.
这是一个探索任务
This is an exploration mission.
让我们探索
Let's explore.
收到
Copy that.
-睁大眼睛，小心背后
- Eyes open, watch your backs.
真的,Mac ?
Really, Mac?
所以我们要跟着一些大鲨鱼
So, we're gonna follow some giant sharks
去一个未知的区域?
to a unknown sector?
男人
Man...
听我说，这简直是蠢到家了
This some dumbass shit, mark my words.
进入第21扇区
Entering sector 21.
开始地理扫描
Commencing geographical scan.
它是如此美丽
It's so beautiful.
你妈妈爱这里胜过一切
Your mum loved this place more than anything.
我很高兴我终于看到了
I'm glad I finally get to see it.
不要习惯了
Don't get used to it.
你这辈子都被禁足了
You're grounded for the rest of your life.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
前方400米，海琪等待
Haiqi 400 meters ahead and holding.
我们现在要去哪里?< / i >
Where are we going now?
进入未知
Into the unknown.
这就是我们来的目的
That's what we came for.
我前面有海琪的追踪器
I've got Haiqi's tracker ahead.
看起来她在打转
Looks like she's circling.
查找
Look up.
这是一种本能的聚集
It's some instinctual gathering.
难以置信的
Incredible.
它们是来交配的
They're here to mate.
这就是为什么海七一直表现得很奇怪
This is why Haiqi has been acting strangely.
哦,太棒了 兆
Oh, great. More megs.
扫描仪检测到一个异常结构
The scanner's detecting an abnormal structure.
不可能
No way.
那是残骸吗?< / i >
Is that a wreck?
这是某种海底观测站
It's some kind of sea floor station.
他们在这里做什么呢?
What could they be doing down here?
里加斯，搜索所有的频谱
Rigas, run all spectrums.
不，那不是残骸
No, that's no wreck.
我正在获取它的热信号
I'm getting heat signatures off it.
就是看不见里面是什么
Just can't see what's inside.
多个宇航服<我>,< / i >
Multiple airlocks,
<我>发电 < / i >
power generation.
所需的资源是惊人的
The resources needed is staggering.
谁会有这样的技术呢?
Who would even have that technology?
声纳显示我们上方有东西
Sonar says there's something above us.
它看起来像潜艇
It looks like a submarine.
让我们来看一看
Let's take a look.
<我>指控 < / i >
Charges set.
起爆区
Priming zone for detonation.
来吧 我们得炸掉这个山脊
Come on. We need to blow this ridge.
好，好，好
Yeah, okay, okay.
我们不想在下面待太久
We don't wanna be down here any longer than needs be.
对，这是唯一一个
Yeah, well, this is the only place
来挖掘这些东西
to mine this stuff.
缓慢而稳定
Slow and steady.
<我>嘿,蒙特斯 < / i >
Hey, Montes.
为什么你可以呆在潜艇里?< / i >
Why do you get to stay in the submarine?
当国王真好
It's good to be the king.
检测到传入对象
Incoming object detected.
放大400%
Zoom in 400%.
Mana One船员在我们下面
Mana One crew is below us.
他们不可能没见过车站
There's no way they haven't seen the station.
我们要做什么?< / i >
What are we gonna do?
我正在给炸药上武器
I'm arming the explosives right now.
你得出去
You have to get out.
<我> ?等等，不，你不能那样做
What? Wait, no, you can't do that.
没时间了 你知道没时间了
There isn't time. You know there isn't time.
需要十分钟才能清除
It will take ten minutes to get clear.
<我>蒙特斯!< / i >
Montes!
对不起,伙计们
Sorry, guys.
<我>蒙特斯!蒙特斯，别这样!< / i >
Montes! Montes, don't do it!
那是什么?< / i >
What was that?
山体滑坡!
Landslide!
我无法超越它 我要穿过
I can't get ahead of it. I'm gonna have to go through.
<我> ?发生什么事情了?< / i >
Guys? What's happening?
我读取到温跃层破裂
I'm reading a thermocline breach.
有什么东西在上面撕开了一个大洞
Something's ripped a giant hole in it.
改变推进器的路线 这是我们仅有的了
Rerouting the thrusters. This is all we've got.
垂直控制是向下的
Vertical control is down.
液压系统没有反应
Hydraulics are non-responsive.
我们是固定的
We're pinned.
进来
Coming in.
- 让我们保持稳定  -是的
-  Hold us steady. -  Yeah.
<我> Jiuming 向下60度
Jiuming. Sixty degrees down.
向前两英尺
Two feet forward.
Jiuming !
Jiuming!
快，快，快!
Go, go, go!
最大推力!最大推力!
Full thrust! Full thrust!
Jiuming !
Jiuming!
不!
No!
没有遥测技术
There's no telemetry.
俯冲1，俯冲2 收到了吗?
Dive 1, Dive 2. Do you copy?
我们这里什么都没有
We've got nothing here.
继续努力，DJ 杰茜，准备救援潜艇，快
Keep trying, DJ. Jess, prep the rescue sub. Stat.
-发生什么事了?-我不知道
- Ugh, what happened? - I don't know.
我们怎么知道他们是否还活着?
How do we know if they're still alive?
准备好救援车
Prep the rescue vehicle.
俯冲1，俯冲2 收到了吗?
Dive 1, Dive 2. Do you copy?
拜托，乔纳斯
Come on, Jonas.
Meiying
Meiying.
——Meiying
- Meiying.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
受到了严重的打击
Took a nasty hit.
叔叔Jiuming吗?
Uncle Jiuming?
九明叔叔在哪里?
Where's Uncle Jiuming?
-他在哪儿?-我们养不了他
- Where is he? - We can't raise him.
嘿 我们一个一个地解决问题
Hey. We work the problems one by one.
我们做摆在我们面前的事情……
We do what's in front of us...
…然后我们做下一件事
...and then we do the next thing.
我们会没事的
We're gonna be okay.
Mac !
Mac!
救援潜艇坏了
The rescue sub isn't working.
电池阵列被故意短路
The battery array was deliberately shorted out.
看起来像是蓄意破坏
It looks like sabotage.
这怎么可能?
How's that possible?
这里不是安全区域
This isn't a secure area.
有30个人在这里工作
There are 30 people who work here.
那要多久才能修好呢?
Well, how long to fix it?
是控制板的问题，麦克，没办法修好
It's the control boards, Mac. There is no fixing it.
现在试试吧
Try it now.
我们的情况如何?
What's our status?
没有通讯，没有暖气
No comms, no heat.
我们正在迅速失去空气
We're losing air fast.
这行不通
This isn't working.
让多余的氧气充血
Flood in my extra O2.
已经完成了
Already done.
我还有最后一个想法
I've got one last idea.
把电源穿过加热电池
Route the power through the heating cell.
我有潜水1 麦克，我找到1号潜水台了
I got Dive 1. Mac, I got Dive 1.
——乔纳斯?
- Jonas?
很高兴听到你的声音，麦克
Good to hear your voice, Mac.
不如听到你的声音好，兄弟
Not as good as it is to hear yours, brother.
跟我说话
Talk to me.
这并不好
It ain't good.
几乎每个系统都坏了，我们正在迅速失去空气
Almost every system is down, and we're losing air fast.
我们穿上紧急潜水服…
We'll get into the emergency dive suits...
我们需要有人送我们过去
and we're gonna need a ride up.
乔纳斯……
Jonas...
这是不可能的
it's not gonna be possible.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
电池阵列 它短路了
The battery array. It shorted out
救援潜艇的控制板
the control board in the rescue sub.
我们正在调查
We're investigating it now.
乔纳斯?
Jonas?
乔纳斯，能听到我说话吗?
Jonas, can you hear me?
乔纳斯，我们找不到你
Jonas, we can't get to you.
我们走着去
We're gonna walk.
我们要穿过战壕走回去
We're gonna walk back across the trench.
去那个海底接收站
Make it into that sea floor station.
我们要进去了
And we're gonna get inside.
然后我们会到达表面
And then we're gonna get to the surface.
那些衣服有两小时的透气时间
Those suits have two hours of air tops.
它们只用于短暂的舱外工作
They're only designed for brief extravehicular work.
我们慢慢来，稳扎稳打 他们会举行
We'll go slow and steady. They'll hold.
有三公里
It's three kilometers.
你在外面会毫无防备的
You'll be defenseless out there.
你想从我这里得到什么，麦克?
What do you want from me, Mac?
这就是我们得到的，这就是我们要做的
This is what we got, and this is what we're gonna do.
我们队里有一半人死了
Half our team is dead,
我不会失去另一半的
and I'm not losing the other half.
开始套装初始化
Beginning suit initialization.
关节执行器工作
Joint actuators functioning.
超声信号通信在线
Ultrasonic signal communications online.
< / i > <我>初始化完成
Initialization complete.
放弃1号潜水，麦克
Abandoning Dive 1, Mac.
无线电无法传送到地面，所以我们要熄火了
The radios won't relay to the surface, so we're going dark.
在另一边跟你说话
Talk to you on the other side.
祝成功,乔纳斯
Godspeed, Jonas.
紧急逃生启动
Emergency escape initiated.
<我>嘿 哇!< / i >
Hey. Whoa!
差点杀了你
Almost killed you.
你到底在干什么?< / i >
The hell are you doing?
省省吧
Saving your ass.
然后走回车站
And walking back to that station.
你在做什么?< / i >
What are you doing?
省省吧
Saving your ass.
然后走回车站
And walking back to that station.
我没有太多的时间 -我们走吧
- Don't have much time. - Let's get going.
<我>——九寨沟 ——哦 < / i >
- Jiu. - Oh.
叔叔，我以为你
Uncle, I thought you--
你不会那么容易摆脱我的
You're not going to get rid of me that easily.
<我>嘿 < / i >
Hey.
<我>嘿 让我查一下
Hey. Let me check.
<我>空气离开…< / i >
Air left...
嘿，你需要冷静下来
Hey, you need to calm down
否则你会耗光氧气的，兰斯
or you're gonna run out of oxygen, Lance.
我想我不能
I don't think i can.
把它当作cosplay
Think of it as cosplay.
或者我们可以玩彩弹游戏
Or we could be paintballing.
就像终极的团队建设练习
Like the ultimate team-building exercise.
我们需要覆盖距离
We need to cover distance
，而meg仍然被占用
while the megs are still occupied.
距离目的地3公里
Three kilometers to destination.
远离megs对我来说很好
Away from the megs is fine by me.
我们是一个强大的团队
We're a strong group.
我们可以这样做
We can do this.
<我>神奇 < / i >
Amazing.
照明由大自然提供
Lighting courtesy of Mother Nature.
<我>这是难以置信的,< / i >
It's incredible,
我们周围到处都是新物种
there are new species all around us.
<我>嘿 看 < / i >
Hey. Look.
看这个 很漂亮 < / i >
Look at this. It's beautiful.
你好，我的小生物——
Hello, my little biolum--
有一条蛇!有一条蛇!< / i >
There's a snake! There's a snake!
把这个怪物从我头上拿开!< / i >
Get this monster off my head!
禁止触摸物品
No touching stuff.
他开始了
He started it.
所有人离开车站
Everyone clear the station.
DJ，乔纳斯节目现在几点了?
DJ, what's our time on Jonas?
他们失踪41分钟了
Forty-one minutes since they went dark.
最多再花一个小时
At best, it'll take another hour
让他们走完这段距离
for them to cover the distance.
听好了
Listen up.
我们知道战壕里有什么流氓行动
We know there's some kind of rogue operation in the trench.
现在，有个混蛋弄伤了他的手指
Now, some bastard's got his fingers
在我们这里的操作中
in our operation here.
那艘潜艇肯定被破坏了
That sub was definitely sabotaged,
所以我们在局里有内奸
so we've got a mole on the station.
DJ，我要你调出所有监控录像
DJ, I want you to pull all surveillance footage
过去24小时里在潜艇湾的人
from the sub bay for the last 24 hours.
杰茜，查一下船员的人事档案，
Jess, run the personnel files on the crew,
寻找任何可疑的东西
look for anything suspect.
我们要抓住这些混蛋，
We're gonna get these sons of bitches,
但我们得小心自己
but we have to watch our own backs.
我们总有一个人负责DCC，明白吗?
One of us mans the DCC at all times, understood?
是的
Yes.
是只有我吗，
Is it just me,
还是在水下走三公里
or does walking three kilometers underwater
听起来很辛苦吗?< / i >
sound like hard work?
这当然不在我的待办事项清单上
It certainly wasn't on my to-do list.
婴儿章鱼 <我> < / i >
Baby octopi.
这么多颜色 这是难以置信的 < / i >
So many colors. That's incredible.
有人想玩游戏吗?< / i >
Anybody wanna play a game?
<我>游戏吗?< / i >
A game?
这不是游戏
This isn't a game.
她的意思是让我们分心
She means to keep our minds occupied.
现在，我的脑子非常满
Right now, my mind is pretty damn occupied.
<我>有一个…有一个…这是…< / i >
There's a... there's a... It's...
<我>兰斯?< / i >
Lance?
那是什么?< / i >
What was it?
- 我没看见  -  Lance在哪里?< / i >
-  I didn't see. -  Where's Lance?
是meg吗?< / i >
Is it a meg?
<我>一些……他出事了 我知道 </ I >
Some... something's happened to him. I know it.
<我>兰斯?< / i >
Lance?
<我> 哦,不 < / i >
No. Oh, no.
我们必须继续前进
We have to keep moving.
<我>不,我们……我们不能把他留在那里
No, we... We can't just leave him out there.
我们得找到他!< / i >
We need to find him!
<我>请Jiuming < / i >
Please, Jiuming.
-对不起 ——< / i >
- I'm sorry. -
<我>他不见了 < / i >
He's gone.
Rigas，掩护我们6点 拍任何会动的东西
Rigas, cover our six. Shoot anything that moves.
你说对了，我会的
You bet your ass I will.
< / i > <我>在线审稿
Comms online.
你怎么了?< / i >
What happened to you?
玛娜一号船员偶然发现了我们的空间站
The Mana One crew stumbled upon our station.
我以压倒性优势击败了他们
I took them out with a landslide.
好吧，这是…这已经失控了
Okay, this is... this is out of control.
你授权了我
You authorized me
不惜一切代价保护我们的行动
to do whatever's necessary to protect our operation.
不
No.
他们没死
They're not dead.
他们现在正往车站走
They are walking right now to the station.
如果他们到了那里，
If they get there,
我们完蛋了
we are screwed.
还有一公里要走，
There's still a kilometer to go,
直接穿过山谷，
straight through that valley,
我们没有
and we don't have
生物发光覆盖我们
the bioluminescence to cover us.
我们会完全暴露在那里
We're going to be totally exposed out there.
我们没有选择
We don't have a choice.
我们只有足够的空气直接通过
We only have enough air to go straight through.
让我们把灯开在低光谱上
Let's keep our lights on low spectrum.
<我>是的 我们可不想吸引笨蛋
Yeah. We don't want to attract the megs.
距离目的地一公里
One kilometer to destination.
- O2检查?< / i >
-  O2 check?
< / i > <我> 65%
65%.
<我> 50 < / i >
50.
< / i > <我> 26%
26%.
这是不够的
It's not gonna be enough.
嘿，看着我 看着我
Hey, look at me. Look at me.
看着我，好吗?重点,好吗?< / i >
Look at me, okay? Focus, okay?
你可以这样做 记住训练
You can do this. Remember the training.
声纳有发现吗?< / i >
Anything on sonar?
我得到了一些东西，就在我的范围的边缘
I got something, right at the edge of my range.
不停地进出
Keeps going in and out.
<我>跟踪我们 < / i >
Stalking us.
<我>接近警戒 < / i >
Proximity alert.
- 是什么?< / i >
-  What is it?
这只是一群鱼
It's just a shoal of fish.
大家保持冷静
Stay calm, everyone.
- [Jiuming] 你还好吗?-是的 < / i >
- [Jiuming] Are you okay? - Yeah.
< / i > <我>继续前进
Keep moving.
哈尔曼氏崖爬藤,Mac
Ayo, Mac.
监控录像里什么都没有
We got jack on the security footage.
有人删了
Somebody deleted it.
为了潜艇湾?
For the sub bay?
为了整个车站
For the whole damn station.
他们很好，但他们不是无所不知
They're good, but they don't know everything.
这是一条带有加密备份的卫星上行链路
There's a satellite uplink with an encrypted backup.
我要去服务器室，
I'm gonna go to the server room,
看看我能不能把它拉下来
see if I can pull it down.
时间吗?
Time?
一小时，50 他们很快就没气了
One hour, 50. They'll be out of air soon.
我正在扫描所有频道，但还没有发现
I'm scanning all channels, but nothing yet.
<我>就是这样 大概400米
That's it. Maybe 400 meters.
<我>警告 < / i >
Warning.
进入氧气储备
Entering oxygen reserves.
你可以这样做
You can do this.
<我>——嗯?-是的 < / i >
- Yeah? - Yeah.
我正在读取
I'm getting a reading.
我们右边有很多联系人
Many contacts to our right.
快来了
Coming in fast.
<我>,兆?< / i >
What, megs?
<我> 小 更快 < / i >
No. Smaller. Faster.
所有人都到车站去!< / i >
Everybody make it to the station!
-走，走! - 警告
- Go, move! -  Warning.
-氧气浓度低 - [Rigas] 来吧
- Oxygen level low. - [Rigas] Come on.
- 来吧 - [Sal] 我没气了
-  Come on. - [Sal] I'm out of air.
他们从山脊那边过来了!< / i >
They're coming over the ridge!
那些东西是什么?< / i >
What are those things?
太远了
It's too far.
我们需要抵抗!< / i >
We need to make a stand!
转身战斗!< / i >
Turn and fight!
<我>来吧!< / i >
Come on!
<我>——Meiying !< / i >
- Meiying!
<我>帮助!打爆他们的头!< / i >
Help! Shoot their head!
<我>——Meiying !——叔叔!< / i >
- Meiying! - Uncle!
我抓住你了!< / i >
I've got you!
坚持住!
Hold on!
他们在咬穿衣服
They're biting through the suit.
<我> Meiying !< / i >
Meiying!
<我> 没有 < / i >
No. No.
坚持住，Curtis!< / i >
Hold on, Curtis!
<我>太多!我们没有机会了!< / i >
Too many! We don't have a chance!
所有人都退后!< / i >
Everybody stay back!
<我>继续!< / i >
Keep going!
<我> Jiuming !< / i >
Jiuming!
没有选择
There's no choice.
你真的很想死，是吗?< / i >
You really want to die, don't you?
必须到达气闸!< / i >
Gotta make it to the airlock!
<我>警告 低空气 < / i >
Warning. Low air.
没用的
It's no use
我在拖你后腿 -低空气
- I'm holding you back. - Low air.
-不太远 ——< / i >
- It's not too far. -
你能做到的!< / i >
You can make it!
<我>警告 低空气 < / i >
Warning. Low air.
<我>——警告 较低的空气 ——< / i >
- Warning. Low air. -
<我>空气耗尽 < / i >
Air depleted.
——<我>叔叔!——< / i >
-  Uncle! -
遮阳板即将失效
Visor failure imminent.
<我> Jiuming !< / i >
Jiuming!
<我> 我们得走了 我们没有选择
Okay. We gotta go. We don't have a choice.
他要回来了!< / i >
He's coming back around!
-哦，天哪! - 加油，加油，加油!< / i >
-  Oh, God! -  Go, go, go!
我们必须重写
We have to do the override.
来，快点
Come on, hurry up.
- Rigas，加油!——< / i >
- Rigas, come on! -
你能做到的 进入!< / i >
You can do it. Get in!
-关上门!< / i >
- Shut the door!
Curtis，你会没事的
Curtis, you'll be okay.
太空服即将内爆
Suit implosion imminent.
-差不多了 差不多了!- [Curtis] 噢，我的天
- Almost there. Almost there! - [Curtis] Oh, my God.
它要爆炸了
It's gonna implode.
给房间减压!< / i >
Depressurize the room!
-不，不，不
- No, no, no.
<我>——不!< / i >
- No!
王八蛋!
Son of a bitch!
我讨厌这些东西!
I hate these things!
嘿,里加斯
Hey, Rigas.
让我们努力保持团结
Let's try to keep it together.
我们还没有脱离危险
We ain't out of the woods yet.
里加斯
Rigas.
大家都到哪里去了?
Where is everybody?
那是什么味道?
What is that smell?
潜水员
Divers.
没有人回家
Nobody home.
我来把门盖住
I'll cover the door.
幕后主使不是我们的朋友
Whoever's running this is not our friend.
我们要尽快联系玛娜一号
We need to contact Mana One ASAP.
你能行吗?
Think you can handle it?
是的 是的,当然
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
他们开采的是什么?
What is this that they're mining?
不管是什么，他们都发过来了
Whatever it is, they're sending it
带着这些吊舱到海面上去
up to the surface with these pods.
嗯 稀土金属
Mmm. Rare earth metals.
它们被用于超导体，
They're used in superconductors,
航空航天和量子计算
aerospace and quantum computing.
光这个盒子就值10亿美元
This box alone could be a billion dollars.
十亿后面有个B?"
"Billion" with a "B?"
是的
Yes.
-玛娜一号
- Mana One.
乔纳斯 通信是实时的
Jonas. Comms are live.
<我> < / i >
Come in.
<我>乔纳斯 得到这个?< / i >
It's Jonas. Getting this?
嘿，你还活着
Hey, you're alive.
你的情况如何?
What's your status?
我们失去了兰斯，萨尔和柯蒂斯
We lost Lance, Sal, and Curtis.
我们在车站
We're at the station.
这是一次流氓采矿行动
It's a rogue mining operation.
下面有人吗?< / i >
Is there anyone down there?
到目前为止我们还没有看到
Not that we've seen so far.
他们已经渗透进了玛娜一号
They've infiltrated Mana One.
营救潜艇被破坏
The rescue sub was sabotaged.
-被谁?-我们正在努力
- By who? - We're working on it.
但是看看这个
But check this out.
我在看视频
I was going over the video
你上次经过那个车站的时间
of when you went over that station before.
看北面
Look at the north side.
看起来像是紧急逃生舱
Looks like emergency escape pods.
它和我们所在的地方相反
It's the opposite side from where we are.
感觉像死了一样
Feels dead in here.
保持密切联系
Stay close.
这些是我的设计
These are my designs.
他们是怎么做到的?
How do they have this?
看来就是这样了
Looks like this is it.
三
On three.
Three.
——再一次 -没用的
-  Again. - It's not gonna work.
在你之后
After you.
啊，这才像话
Ah, this is more like it.
我们打开荚果，离开这里吧
Let's crack open a pod and get out of here.
没有在这里
Nothing here.
这些控制失灵了
These controls ain't working.
我们得关上舱门
We need to close the hatch.
在上面
On it.
伙计们，那不是我
Guys, that wasn't me.
乔纳斯，既然你在这里，
Jonas, now that I have you here,
我们需要坦诚地谈谈
we need to talk candidly.
我完全控制了这个站，
I have full control of the station,
我已经把这个房间锁起来了
and I've locked down this room.
杰斯?
Jess?
你的命在我手里
Your life is in my hands.
你在干什么，杰茜?
What are you doing, Jess?
这些是你的朋友
These are your friends.
他们和你在一起很多年了
They've been with you for years.
我知道这很痛
I know it hurts.
因为我更喜欢
And we're talking because I'd prefer
我们在同一边
we were on the same side.
赚那么多钱，就没有意义了
All making so much money, it ceases to have meaning.
你要给我们钱?
You're offering us money?
我们的三个朋友都因你而死
Three of our friends are dead because of you.
你以为我会忘记这事吗?
You think I'm gonna forget about that?
不，不，不，不!那是第一个逃生舱!
No, no, no, no, no! That's the first escape pod!
王八蛋!
Son of a bitch!
<我>里加斯?Rigas，你可以救美英
Rigas? Rigas, you can save Meiying.
拿起那把矛枪，朝乔纳斯的心脏开枪
Take that speargun and shoot Jonas in the heart.
别开枪打他
Don't shoot him.
这样做
Do it.
去做吧
Go ahead.
这是美英生存的唯一途径
It's the only way Meiying survives.
这样做
Do it.
里加斯!
Rigas!
做到!
Do it!
-去吧!——没有 我很抱歉
- Do it! - No. I'm sorry.
我很抱歉 对不起，我不能 我不能 我不能
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I can't. I can't. I can't.
那是最后一个吊舱
That was the last pod.
我告诉过你那不行
I told you that wouldn't work.
让我听电话
Put me on.
哦，很抱歉事情发展到这个地步
Oh, sorry it had to come to this.
<我>所以…< / i >
So...
我们一周后就回去工作，
we'll be back at work in a week,
用你的技术来获取我们想要的东西
using your technology to take whatever we want.
您的研究所将成为我们使用的平台
Your institute'll be a platform that we use
掠夺海洋几十年
to plunder the ocean for decades.
报应会报应你的
Karma will get you.
在你开始抱怨生态系统之前，
And before you start whining about the ecosystem,
<我>谁在乎呢?我们会赚几十亿的
who cares? We'll make billions.
没有人会看到我们造成的伤害
And no one is going to see the damage we do.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
Jess，我已经把
Jess, I've already dispatched
一个清洁小组到Mana One
a clean-up crew to Mana One.
<我>完成 < / i >
Finish this.
我们怎么开门?
How do we open the door?
如果我们能切断与地表的通讯…
If we could cut the comm link to the surface...
她什么都控制不了
she couldn't control anything.
但它在第一个房间里，
But it's back in the first room,
这扇门是进不去的
and there's no getting through this door.
这个气闸还能用!
This airlock still works!
你为什么要穿过气闸?没有豆荚
Why would you go through the airlock? There's no pod.
我要游到我们进来的气闸那里
I'll swim to the airlock where we came in
然后重写
and do the override.
你没有西装 这怎么可能呢?
You have no suit. How could it work?
水在压力下不会压缩，
Water doesn't compress under pressure,
所以如果他能让水进入窦腔，
so if he can force water in his sinus cavities,
他能活30到60秒
he could survive 30, maybe 60 seconds
在他昏过去之前
before he passes out.
-有可能
- It is possible.
我们一个一个地解决问题
We work the problems one by one.
我们先做眼前的事，然后再做下一件事
We do what's in front of us, then we do the next thing.
如果有人能做到这一点
If anyone can do this,
这是你的
it's you.
他不会被压力压垮吗?
Won't he be crushed by the pressure?
事情不是这样的
It doesn't work like that.
你没见过穿金属服的鱼吧?
You don't see fish wearing metal suits, do you?
这是关于空气的 它在压力下反应
It's about air. It reacts under pressure.
这就是为什么他要把它从鼻窦里吹出来
And that's why he has to blow it out of his sinuses.
大家好，环保主义者
Hey there, tree hugger.
乔纳斯·泰勒，生态战士，
Jonas Taylor, eco-warrior,
打好仗
fighting the good fight.
你猜怎么着?
Well, guess what?
你输了
You lost.
我在马尼拉的监狱里待了两年
I spent two years in a Manila prison
在你和你的生态怪胎朋友之后
after you and your eco-freak buddies
我们的船被扣押了
had our ship seized.
我每天都在想你
I thought about you every single day.
你都不记得我了，对吧?
You don't even remember me, do you?
——嗯?
- Hmm?
没有?
No?
蒙特斯
Montes.
这个世界上有无数的人渣
There's a million scumbags in this world.
很难跟踪所有的人
It's hard to keep track of all of 'em.
我想我去不了了!
I don't think I can make it!
你能做到的 没关系
You can do it. It's okay.
我们会死的!
We're going to die!
没事的，没事的
It's ok, it's ok.
Meiying !
Meiying!
清理接近玛娜一号的船员
Clean up crew approaching Mana One.
<我> 我们处于警戒状态
About time. We are on alert.
每个人都被限制在自己的房间里
Everyone confined to their quarters.
我们需要控制Mana One
We need to get control of Mana One
和处置任何负债
and dispose of any liabilities.
有什么紧急情况?
What's the emergency?
我进入了安全备份系统
I got into the security backup.
看看这个
Look at this.
杰西使救援潜艇失灵
Jess disabled the rescue sub.
——什么?——看
- What? - Watch.
好像她在修一样，对吧?
Like she could be repairing it, right?
但是不，等等
But no, wait.
是蒙特斯的代课老师
It's Montes' sub.
那是我们离开这里的车
That's our ride out of here.
液压系统有个漏洞
There's a leak in the hydraulics.
捕食者对抗系统失效了
Predator countermeasures are down.
我们过不了米格斯了
We'll never make it past the megs.
我们需要分散注意力
We need a distraction.
点亮车站 巨怪会攻击它
Light up the station. The megs will attack it.
是的 然后杀了我们
Yeah. And kill us.
只要我们够快就不会
Not if we're fast enough.
Jiuming !
Jiuming!
-嘿，里加斯 ——请讲?
-  Hey, Rigas. - Yep?
刚才我还以为你要杀了我呢
For a moment, I thought you were gonna kill me back there.
她确实说了一枪打在你心脏上
Well, she did say to shoot you in the heart.
我知道你根本就没有
And I know for a fact you ain't got one of those.
谢谢你的努力
Thank you for working.
得关上舱门，乔纳斯
Gotta close the hatch, Jonas.
我们都会死的
We're all gonna die.
他会成功的
He's gonna make it.
不，他不是
No, he's not.
-他会没事的 ——不!
- He's gonna make it. - No!
我们得关上舱门!
We have to close the hatch!
-关上它!乔纳斯!
-  Close it! Jonas!
我在这里!
I'm here!
-就是他!
-  That's him!
好险啊
That was close.
太近
Too close.
你应该关上舱门的
You should have shut the hatch.
是的 美英会杀了我的
Yeah. Meiying would have killed me.
不过你想过了
You thought about it, though.
是的 我们考虑过
Yeah. We thought about it.
不是吗，Rigas?
Didn't we, Rigas?
闭嘴
Shut up.
只是一点点
Just a little bit.
很有趣
Very funny.
炸药?
Explosives?
看看这个
Check this out.
看看还有什么
Look what else.
这有什么问题吗?
Is that gonna be a problem?
这是热层上的一个洞
It's a hole in the thermal layer.
肯定是矿井爆炸造成的
It must have been caused by the mining explosions.
它最终会被封住的
It will seal up eventually.
最终呢?
Eventually?
是的 一小时之内
Yeah. Within an hour.
米格斯能跟着我们走吗?
Can the megs follow us through?
我希望不是
I hope not.
孩子们，我不想伤害你们，
Boys, I don't want to harm you,
但我需要你离开这个房间
but I do need you to come out of this room.
这是杰斯 她有三个士兵
It's Jess. She's got three soldiers.
是的 该走了
Yeah. It's go time.
把这个
Take this.
-这是怎么回事?-是泰瑟枪
- The hell is this? - It's a Taser.
开放
Open up.
他们想杀乔纳斯
They tried to kill Jonas,
他们肯定会杀了我们
they're definitely gonna kill us.
好的,听着 计划是这样的
Okay, listen. Here's the plan.
我数到三，你就开门
On the count of three, you'll open the door
我要给他们喷胡椒喷雾
and I'mma pepper spray 'em.
对，然后你关上门，等着
Right, and you'll shut the door and you're gonna wait.
那就出去用泰瑟枪
Then go out there and use the Taser.
一，二，三
One, two, three.
-不，麦克，不!不,苹果……
-  No, Mac, no! No, Mac...
它燃烧!它燃烧!
It burns! It burns!
-对不起!
-  I'm sorry!
沉睡的时间
Sleepy time.
-那是什么?
- What's that?
麻烦
Trouble.
所以，我们走得很快
So, we're walking fast and with
决心很大，这很好
a lot of determination, which is great.
但计划到底是什么?
But what exactly is the plan here?
他们有武器，而我们没有
They're armed and we're not.
好了 你在想什么?
All righty. So what are you thinking?
你在想什么?
What are you thinking?
你和我去找麦克和DJ
You and I find Mac and DJ.
里加斯，拿你能拿的东西
Rigas, grab what you can.
保护好十二宫杀手，这样我们就能离开这东西了
Secure a Zodiac so we can get off this thing.
摇滚
Rock and roll.
如果美英和你一起去最安全
Safest if Meiying goes with you.
我会用我的生命保护她
I'll protect her with my life.
我会用我的保护她
And I'll protect her with mine.
不
No.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我告诉过你在走出那扇门之前等一等
I told you to wait before you went out that door.
-你的眼睛怎么样了?-我的眼睛刺痛
- How's your eyes? - My eye stings.
如果我们爬上通信阵列，
If we climb up to the communications array,
我们可以绕过DCC呼叫帮助
we can bypass the DCC and we can call for help.
我们该说什么?
What are we supposed to say?
嗯…恐怖行动吗?
Uh... terrorist action?
-是的，很好 恐怖行动 -对，恐怖行动
- Yeah, good. Terrorist action. - Yeah, terrorist action.
——好的 -你有更好的主意吗?
-  Okay. - You got a better idea?
——冻结!
-  Freeze!
哦,不
Oh, no.
DJ !DJ !
DJ! DJ!
搞什么鬼?
What the hell?
哇!是的,宝贝!得到一些!
Wow! Yeah, baby! Get some!
-嗨 -快跑，麦克!快跑!
- Hey. - Run, Mac! Run!
-快，快，快!
-  Go, go, go!
传播出去!找到他们
Spread out! Find 'em.
你有泰瑟枪吗?现在你会游泳了?
You got Tasers? Now you can swim?
突然间你就像蝙蝠侠一样跑来跑去
All of a sudden you run around like you're frickin' Batman.
-当然
- Hell yeah.
上次之后，你们都求我回来
After last time, y'all begged me to come back.
-“DJ，哦，我们一家人，DJ ”
-"DJ, oh, we family, DJ."
“DJ，我们需要你 ”好吧 的赌注
"DJ, we need you." Yeah, all right. Bet.
但我不傻
But I ain't stupid.
我接受了训练，学会了如何战斗，
I trained up, I learned how to fight,
我学会了游泳，
I learned how to swim,
不带背包我哪都不会去
and I will never go anywhere without my survival pack.
-生存包?-是的
- Survival pack? - Yeah.
看看这个
Check this out.
嗯 过来，宝贝 到这里来
Mmm-hmm. Come here, baby. Come here.
Bam
Bam.
是啊，我还做过毒头子弹，
Yeah, I even made poison-tipped bullets,
就像大白鲨2
just like Jaws 2.
来吧，DJ!我们走，我们走
Come on, DJ! Let's go, let's go.
这太疯狂了
This is insane.
冻结,混蛋
Freeze, assholes.
是的,冻结
Yeah, freeze.
明白了吗?
You got this?
刚才真是倒霉透了
That was some unfortunate shit back there.
不,请!不要开枪!
No, please! Don't shoot!
我知道你在找我和乔纳斯
I know you're looking for me and Jonas.
我也知道你不会说中文，
I also know you don't speak Chinese,
但我说出来是为了分散你们的注意力
but I'm speaking it to distract you guys,
因为我的朋友要从背后攻击你
because my friend is about to attack you from behind.
怎么啦？
What?
——抽油
-  sucker.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
-痴心妄想，麦克
- Wishful thinking, Mac.
这不是鼻中隔偏曲吗
If it ain't the deviated septum.
-船要开了
- Boat's leaving.
我们的情况如何?
What's our status?
b队来了 预计十分钟后到达
Bravo team are inbound. ETA, ten minutes.
太好了
Excellent.
你在这里做什么?
Uh, what are you doing here?
嗯
Mmm.
-你没事吧?-是的
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
乔纳斯在玛娜一号
Jonas is on Mana One.
我们得马上封锁这个地方
We need to lock this place down now.
从上到下搜索整个车站
Search the station top to bottom.
确保人员的安全，
Secure personnel in their quarters,
杀了其他人
kill anyone else.
走吧!走吧!
Go! Go!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
哦,伙计们?
Uh, guys?
我们有大麻烦了
We've got a big problem.
我们跟踪了三个megs
We tracked three megs
在缺口关闭前逃离
that escaped before the breach closed.
我们得找个好借口
We're gonna need a good cover story for this.
嗯，这应该不难
Well, that shouldn't be hard.
大家都知道乔纳斯和九明鲁莽行事
Everyone knows Jonas and Jiuming were reckless.
不，我们需要一个英雄
No, we need a hero.
比如，有人出现了
Like, someone to emerge
从这场不可预见的悲剧中，
from this unforeseeable tragedy,
谁能担任领导职务
who can step into a leadership position
在研究所
at the Institute.
杰茜，你准备好升职了吗?
Jess, are you ready for promotion?
我感谢你的信任
I appreciate your confidence.
<我>杰斯!< / i >
Jess!
这是温跃层裂口造成的
It's from the thermocline breach.
但是你可以放松
But you can relax.
这个地方吗?Meg-proof
This place? Meg-proof.
乔纳斯一直都很害怕，
I mean, Jonas was always afraid of this,
但我认为，在追踪者和武装直升机之间，
but I think, between trackers and gunships,
我们可以解决这个问题，走出困境
we can solve the problem and come out the other side
具有显著的正PR旋转
with a significant positive PR spin.
好的，我这就去
Yeah, I'm on it.
我还在想……
I was also thinking...
现在该做什么?
What now?
这是我们唯一的出路 我们必须接受它
It's our only way off. We have to take it.
但那东西的射程不够
But that thing doesn't have the range
带我们去大陆
to get us to the mainland.
你担心目的地吗?
You're worried about the destination?
前一百码呢?
What about the first hundred yards?
我们就会死在那里
That's where we goin' die.
我们划得很慢
We paddle out slow.
没有引擎 最小的运动
No engines. Minimal motion.
我们不会看起来像食物
We won't look like food.
等安全了，我们就逃跑 嗯?
When we're clear, we make a run for it. Huh?
我们开始吧
Let's do it.
我还是觉得我们看起来像食物
I still think we look like food.
嘘 安静,每一个人
Shh. Quiet, everyone.
桨缓慢
Paddle slowly.
这种熟悉感令人不快
This feels unpleasantly familiar.
我只希望能比上次顺利
I just hope it goes better than last time.
上次发生了什么?
What happened last time?
你不会想知道的
You don't wanna know.
哦 他来了
Oh. Here he comes.
快，快，快!
Go, go, go!
我们不要把他们活着带回来
Let's not bring 'em back alive.
你知道怎么开这车吧?
You do know how to drive this thing, right?
停!马上把引擎关掉
Stop! Stop the engine right now.
否则你会引来美女
Or you will attract the megs.
好吧 保持淡定
Okay. Be still.
-没有任何动议
- No motion whatsoever.
我打针了
I have the shot.
把它
Take it.
-趴下!-伙计，做好你的工作
- Get down! -  Mate, do your job.
-开枪吧 -不像看上去那么容易
- Take the bloody shot. - It's not easy as it looks.
他抓住他们了!他把它们吃了!
He got 'em! He ate 'em!
他吃掉了整条船!
He ate the whole boat!
发生了什么事?
What happened?
Jess死了
Jess is dead.
——什么?-我们稳定了Mana One
- What? - We stabilized Mana One
但是Taylor和Zhang逃走了
but Taylor and Zhang have escaped.
你想让我怎么做?
What do you want me to do?
<我>修复它!杀了他们!< / i >
Fix it! Kill them!
你这样做，你写你自己的票
You do this, you write your own ticket.
你已经为生活做好了准备
You are set for life.
好吧
Okay.
他们能去的地方只有几个
There's only a couple places they could make it to.
你在哭吗，蒙特斯?——< / i >
- Are you crying, Montes? -
有megs的迹象吗?
Any sign of the megs?
负的
Negative.
这东西不可能成功的
There's no way this thing's gonna work.
会成功的
It's gonna work.
伙计，你更有可能把自己炸飞
Bloke, you got more chance of blowing up yourself
比一个大
than one of the megs.
至少我不会被吃掉
At least I won't get eaten.
哈，我听到了
Ha, I hear that.
乔，你能给我做一个吗?
Jo, can you make me one?
我掩护你，麦克
I got you covered, Mac.
我们得想办法警告大家
We have to find a way to warn people.
以防巨兽向陆地移动
In case the megs move towards land.
我们东南方向60公里处有个岛
There's an island 60 klicks southeast of us.
它被列为有人居住的地方
It's listed as inhabited.
谁住的?
Inhabited by who?
这个名字或多或少可以翻译成……
The name more or less translates to...
有趣的岛
Fun Island.
有趣的岛?
Fun Island?
是啊!
Yeah!
欢迎来到欢乐岛 我们的度假村什么都有
Welcome to Fun Island. Our resort has everything.
餐厅，太棒了
The restaurant, amazing.
迪斯科，太棒了
The disco, incredible.
-还有我们的水疗，太棒了 ——哦
- And our spa, to die for. -  Oh.
——哦 ——OMG
-  Oh. -  OMG.
这是我们的特色菜 海鲜惊喜!
It's our special dish. Seafood Surprise!
哇!我不知道从哪里开始
Wow! I wouldn't know where to start.
那就别错过烤鲨鱼了
Well, just don't miss out on the grilled shark.
-优秀的东西!优秀的东西!
- Pippin! Pippin!
优秀的东西!
Pippin!
-哇，那是什么?-优秀的东西!
- Whoa, what is that? -  Pippin!
他们在逃避什么?
What are they running from?
你第一次看竞技表演吗?
Your first time at the rodeo?
你出生前我就和你爸爸一起工作了
I worked with your dad since before you were born.
他从来没给我惹过这种麻烦
I never had this kind of trouble from him.
你能把手机放下吗?
Can you put your phone down?
辛苦了这么多年，我们终于放假了，
After all these hard years we're finally on vacation,
享受这一刻
savor the moment.
是啊，我也吼了他
Yeah, and I yelled at him too.
我已经有400个赞了
I've already got 400 likes.
我正坐在天堂里
I'm sitting in paradise
而你却毁了它!
and you are ruining it!
谁会这么做?谁……
Who does that? Who...
毁了别人的天堂?
ruins paradise for other people?
嘿,宝贝
Hey, baby.
想在我背上擦点油吗?
Wanna rub some oil on my back?
没有?
No?
我的正面怎么样?
How 'bout my front?
电子战
Ew.
过来
Come over.
怎么啦？
What?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
桃之夭……
Yaoyao...
你愿意嫁给我吗?
Will you marry me?
找到它，白痴!
Find it, idiot!
等等!
Wait!
你找到了吗?
Have you found it?
嘿
Hey.
桃之夭
Yaoyao.
——桃之夭!桃之夭!
- Yaoyao! Yaoyao!
这看起来不太好
This doesn't look good.
里加斯，快带我们过去!
Rigas, get us there fast!
切断手机上行链路
Kill the cell phone uplink.
这件事对我们有很大的影响
There's a lot of exposure for us on this.
赶紧搞定乔纳斯和他的团队，
Take care of Jonas and his team quickly,
和安静
and quietly.
大家都从水里出来!
Everybody out of the water!
——鲨鱼!鲨鱼!-回到海滩上去!
-  Shark! Shark! -  Get back on the beach!
-从水里出来!
- Get out of the water!
回到沙滩上，每一个…
Get back on the beach, every...
移动通信中断 结束 < / i >
Mobile comms are down. Over.
听到了吗，伙计们?
You copy, guys?
——鳄鱼!
-  Crocodile!
那是什么?
What is that?
-快点，快点!-上直升机
-  Move, move! - Get into the chopper.
——现在!跟她走!
- Now! Go with her!
嗯 嗯
Mmm. Mmm.
每个人都出去!
Everybody out!
鲨鱼!
Shark!
-回去!-不要下水!
-  Go back! - Don't go into the water!
有鲨鱼!
There's a shark!
到海滩上去!
Get on the beach!
回去!
Go back!
我们必须拯救他们
We have to save them.
-我不会离开你的-手机坏了
- I'm not leaving ya. - Cell phone's down.
喂?喂?
Hello? Hello?
-没有信号 -没得选
-  No signal. - There's no choice.
-她说得对 -没信号了，伙计们
- She's right. -  We got no signal, guys.
嘿，你们两个!想办法寻求帮助
Hey, you two! Find a way to call for help.
让每个人都知道发生了什么
Let everyone know what happened.
来吧!来吧!这种方式!这种方式!
Come on! Come on! This way! This way!
你要躲起来
You're gonna hide.
看到那个救生塔了吗?
See that lifeguard tower?
-是的 -你去那里就待在那里
- Yeah. - You go there and you stay there.
这不是那种事
This is not one of those things
我让你做点什么
where I tell you to do something,
你说"是"
you say "yes,"
然后你想怎么做就怎么做
and then you do whatever you want.
明白吗?
Understand?
是的
Yes.
你不是在耍我吧?
You're not messing with me?
不
No.
如果我担心你，我就没法做我该做的事
I can't do what I need to do if I'm worried about you.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
答应我你会回来的
Promise me you'll come back.
你知道我爱你
You know I love you.
哦,狗屎
Oh, shit.
桑尼
Sonny.
-看看这个
- Check that out.
嘿，老兄 你有电话吗?
Hey, yo, my man. You got a phone?
大家都在逃避什么?
What's everyone running from?
那是什么鬼东西?
What the hell was that?
3 mb
Three megs.
我们三个
Three of us.
我们每人拿一辆水上摩托车
We each grab a jet ski.
让他们把它赶走
Get them to chase it away
离开这些人，出海
from these people and out to sea.
然后我们用鱼叉叉他们
Then we harpoon them.
你是说那些偷工减料的，
Oh, you mean with those jerry-rigged,
也许有用，也许会杀死我们的鱼叉?
maybe-they-work, maybe-they-kill-us harpoons?
是的
Yeah.
这是个糟糕的主意
It's a terrible idea.
你有更好的吗?
You got a better one?
不 不
No. No.
-那我们就说定了 -是的
- Then we're agreed. - Yeah.
——好 ——太棒了
- Good. - Great.
蒙特斯!
Montes!
大便
Shit.
我们走老路吧
Let's go old school.
座机也坏了
The landline's down, too.
好了，安全了 我们走吧
Okay, coast is clear. Let's go.
他们能走路吗?
They can walk?
大便
Shit.
就是这些东西
It's those things.
他们还没发现我们
They haven't spotted us yet.
——好的
- Okay.
你这里还有什么?
What else you got in here?
紧急的东西
Emergency stuff.
好吧
Okay.
真的吗?避孕套吗?
Really? Condoms?
不同类型的紧急情况
Different kind of emergencies.
递给我
Hand me that.
把你嘴里的口香糖递给我
Now hand me that gum in your mouth.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
只有一个滑雪板
There's only one ski.
把你的鱼叉给我
Give me your harpoons.
你确定吗?
You sure?
哦……
Oh...
-我来吧 -祝你好运
- I got this. -  Good luck.
我们需要更多的火力
We need more firepower.
是的
Yeah.
我有个主意 我们走吧
I have an idea. Let's go.
这次不会了，泰勒
Not this time, Taylor.
<我>我们 < / i >
Vamos.
应该是这里
This should be the place.
来吧
Come on.
我们在找什么?
What are we looking for?
硝酸铵
Ammonium nitrate.
你在做炸弹?
You're making a bomb?
这东西和TNT炸药一样强大
This stuff is as powerful as TNT.
——嘿!
-  Hey!
-进去!进入!
- Get in! Get in!
冻结!
Freeze!
来吧!
Come on!
来吧，看看他有没有手机
Come on, let's see if he's got a phone.
我有卫星电话 我考了sat…
I got the sat phone. I got the sat...
我接电话了 你为什么偷他的钱?
I got the phone. Why you stealing his money?
——什么?他不会需要的
- What? He's not gonna need it.
哦
Uh-oh.
-好狗狗 漂亮的狗
- Nice doggies. Nice doggies.
好的,里加斯
Okay, Rigas.
我数到三，我们就跑
On the count of three, we're gonna bolt.
一个 两个 三!
One. Two. Three!
搞什么鬼?嘿!
What the hell? Hey!
等DJ!等DJ!
Wait for DJ! Wait for DJ!
他们就在我们后面!
They're right behind us!
我们躲在这里吧!
Let's hide in here!
来吧 来吧 到这里来 到这里来
Come on. Come on. Come here. Come here.
-怎么回事?-嗨，DJ 嗨,里加斯
- What the hell?